Happy New Year, everyone.
As of today, Detective Conan is...
Congrats!
30th Anniversary!!
celebrating its 30th anniversary!
This series has continued for this long
thanks to the support
of viewers of the TV series and movies, and Shonen Sunday readers.
Thank you very much!
We'll keep striving to pay back
your unwavering belief in us,
so we appreciate your continued support.
BEIKA AQUARIUM
Mune ga Dokidoki
Song by The High-Lows
My name is Kudo Shinichi.
I'm a high school detective.
This story is from before
I was given a mysterious drug...
...and became Conan.
We've finally reached
our 30th anniversary!
We'll keep on solving cases together.
There is always only one truth!
Episode "ZERO"
Kudo Shinichi and the Aquarium Case
"Episode 'ZERO'
Kudo Shinichi and the Aquarium Case!"
BEIKA AQUARIUM
Shinichi!
You're late.
You can't be late when you invited me.
Sorry. Something came up.
Why didn't you wait at the entrance?
I had to look for you.
I felt an irresistible urge
to see the sharks.
It's a message from Sonoko.
Her cold's a lot better now.
Oh, really?
Let's hurry up and check the
place out for your whatever plan.
It's not the "whatever plan."
It's the Super Aquarium
Romantic Reunion Plan!
Super Aquarium
Romantic Reunion
PLAN
First, I'll invite my dad to this aquarium
where he'll meet my mom...
in this magical place surrounded by fish.
They'll remember how they felt
when they loved each other...
and start living together again!
Wasn't it you who came up
with this plan?
Yeah, but Sonoko's the one who named it.
But couldn't you have
come to check it out yourself?
But I haven't been to the aquarium before.
I felt anxious about coming alone.
I know you didn't want to come to
this romantic date spot with me.
But Sonoko caught a cold.
You were my only option.
I-It's not that I didn't want to come!
Then let's go to the aquarium café, too.
What?
They have lots of cute items on their menu.
Let me know what you think
so I can help my parents.
Yeah, yeah.
That's just an excuse.
Maybe they shouldn't meet
in front of the sharks...
They have a bad reputation.
I actually wanted to come with Shinichi...
Hey, Shinichi.
Yeah?
Tada! What do you think?
About what?
My clothes.
I like this dress.
It's not bad.
That's all?
If you need an opinion on
your clothes so badly, ask your mom.
Aren't you having dinner with her tonight?
Huh?
H-How do you know that?
Oh, wow!
It's a spotted eagle ray!
I hate when he acts like this.
He'll suddenly act like he read your mind,
but he won't explain how he knows.
Answer me!
I haven't told my dad or Sonoko!
How'd you know I'm meeting my mom?
You didn't look through my phone, did you?
After you checked Sonoko's email,
you checked a previous message.
I naturally assumed you had plans after this
and were confirming the time.
B-But you didn't see the screen.
I could tell from your finger's movements.
And that you're seeing your mom, too.
What? That doesn't answer my question.
You've got fashion magazines
you don't usually buy in your bag.
What?
There's a business card
stuck between the pages.
Considering your confidence
in your outfit today,
it's clear you were asked to be a
reader model, had some shots taken,
and bought a magazine because
you were in a good mood.
You can brag that you
might be in the next issue.
You should be happy.
They don't give business cards
to just anyone they photograph.
You'll probably be in the magazine.
But in this area, model scouts only hang out
around the main street on Third.
That's a little out of the way if
you're coming to this aquarium.
Why did you take that path?
There was somewhere you wanted
to go before coming here.
I knew the answer when I saw your lips.
My lips?
Yeah.
They're shining a little.
You don't wear lip balm, so you
probably ate something oily.
There are fast food restaurants
on that street,
so it's possible you missed breakfast
and grabbed a burger.
But since you want to eat at
the café here, that's out.
Which means you had a light snack...
of supermarket samples.
The supermarket on that street
has great pre-made dishes,
and they have a sale today.
That means you're feeding your dad
pre-made dishes for dinner tonight.
Why would you do that when
you're frugal and a good cook?
Because you don't have time to cook.
You're having dinner with someone tonight.
Naturally, you'll proudly wear the outfit
that caught the scout's eye.
You're not having dinner
with Sonoko, who's sick.
It was obvious enough from your expression,
but that only leaves your mom.
But it looks like you have
another reason you can't cook.
Shinichi?
Ran, go back to the entrance
and call an employee.
What?
Hurry!
Shinichi.
Excuse me! Let me through!
Let me through, please!
Let me through!
I said, let me—
Hey, are you okay?
Stand back!
Move away from him.
Who are you?
This isn't good.
He's not breathing.
One stab through the heart.
The weapon is that knife
sticking through a plastic bag.
Shinichi!
I brought an employee.
Seal the aquarium's exits,
and call the police.
What? Th-The police?
Hurry!
O-Okay!
Don't let the other guests approach the body.
Th-The body?
Is he dead?
Yeah. Someone inside
the aquarium stabbed him.
But how? I didn't hear a scream.
How did you know?
The smell.
The smell?
Red blood cells contain a protein that
carries oxygen called hemoglobin.
It's mostly made of iron.
When you lick a cut,
doesn't it taste like rusted iron?
Naturally, it smells like iron, too.
I didn't smell anything like that, though.
They're like sharks.
Sharks?
Sharks can smell one drop of blood
diluted to one part per million.
Their ears are even sharper,
allowing them to hear frequencies as low
as 40 hertz from two kilometers away.
They approach using their sense of smell,
determine their prey's exact location
by their electric fields, and attack.
They head to the crime scene
when they smell blood.
They use all their senses
to find the culprit.
They tear into their prey with the sharp
teeth of evidence until they admit defeat.
That's what a detective does.
BEIKA AQUARIUM
I see.
ENTRANCE
EXIT
So the self-important young man
commanding the crime scene
is you, Kudo-kun.
Ran and I happened to be at the crime scene.
I asked if anyone saw the culprit,
but no one did.
Is that right? So...
Huh?
Are you two on a date
at the aquarium?
Is that how it looks?
I-It's not like that at all!
I'm joking!
If you get flustered,
he'll think it really is a date.
I'm surprised you can joke
when someone's dead.
It seems the weapon is
this knife next to the body.
The victim was stabbed
through this plastic bag.
The culprit did it to prevent the victim's
blood from getting on themselves.
They turned the blade sideways so it would
slip between his ribs and hit his heart.
They carefully withdrew the blade from under
his jacket so blood wouldn't spill everywhere.
Then they hid the wound
with his jacket, and left.
Surely the victim screamed.
There must be witnesses.
No. Look at the back of his neck.
Someone pressed a stun gun into his neck.
If he was knocked unconscious before he
was stabbed, he couldn't have screamed.
I see.
The blood was still flowing when I arrived,
so he was probably stabbed
a few minutes earlier.
Also, the stun gun is
inside his breast pocket.
This must be it.
The culprit probably drew the victim's
attention to the bottom of the tank
by saying there was an unusual fish.
They hit him with the stun gun while he was
leaning against the tank, which knocked him out.
Instead of falling dramatically, the victim
inconspicuously slumped to the ground,
so they could take their time
stabbing him to death.
Then the culprit could be an
acquaintance of the victim.
But there are no cards, licenses,
or even a business card in his wallet.
We'll have to identify the victim first.
Oh, actually...
The victim is Shumoto Kunihiro-san,
26 years old.
He works at a gas station in Haido City.
Today, he canceled his shift
because he had something to do.
Maybe the victim brought his girlfriend here.
A woman who is around 160 centimeters tall,
wearing a miniskirt, and likes dolphins.
H-How do you know that?
The victim's phone was in his pocket,
so I called a random number
in his contacts and called it.
"I found this phone.
Do you know who it belongs to?"
They told me his name,
so I asked, "I'd like to return it.
Do you know where he is now?"
They told me where he works, so
I called the gas station, too.
I told him not to do it.
It's fine. I told them the next time
they get a call like that,
they should tell the caller
to take the phone to a police box.
You're unbelievable.
Did his employer tell you
about his lady friend?
No. I looked at the receipt
inside the victim's wallet.
The receipt?
Yes. It's from the aquarium café.
It was issued about 15 minutes
before the body was found.
BEIKA AQUARIUM
AQUARIUM
CAFÉ
RECEIPT
COFFEE
TEA
DOLPHIN KEY CHAIN
TOTAL
TENDERED
CHANGE
The receipt lists one coffee as well as one tea,
so he must have been with someone.
The timestamp is five minutes
before the dolphin show,
so they probably waited at
the café for it to start.
The receipt also lists a dolphin
key chain sold by the café,
but the victim doesn't have it.
I can only imagine he gave it
to his girlfriend.
What about the 160 centimeters
and the miniskirt, then?
You're still too innocent to get it.
What does that mean? Gross.
Wh-What do you mean, Kudo-kun?
It's the smell of perfume.
Perfume?
You can smell women's perfume on the
victim's shoulder, elbow, and thigh.
Women apply perfume to various places.
If the smell got on the victim
while she was holding his arm,
the smell on his shoulder must come from
the perfume on her earlobes or hair.
The victim is about 180 centimeters tall,
so based on the location of the perfume,
the woman is about 165 centimeters tall.
Since she likely wore high heels to her date,
subtract five to eight centimeters.
That would make her
around 160 centimeters tall.
The smell on his elbow is from
the perfume on her wrists.
The smell on his thigh is from
the perfume on her skirt.
Based on the locations and her height,
she's probably wearing a miniskirt.
Normally, you only
apply perfume to one location.
Does that mean
she doesn't often wear perfume?
You can't be sure.
If you wear the same perfume all the
time, you get used to the smell.
Sometimes, you'll apply extra
thinking no one can smell it.
That's what my mom told me.
But why won't
that woman come forward?
Her boyfriend is dead.
Who knows?
Maybe they haven't been dating long,
and she doesn't want to get involved.
Maybe she's the one who killed him.
In any case, you should collect all the phones,
cameras, and video cameras from the guests.
Someone may have caught the
culprit stabbing the victim.
DO NOT ENTER
WITHOUT AUTHORIZATION
STAFF ONLY
Come on, Kudo-kun!
There are over a hundred of these!
You want us to check all of these?
And most of the images are of fish...
I'm sure they are.
You're sure?
NEW MESSAGE
DISMISS
VIEW
NEW MESSAGE
DISMISS
VIEW
NEW MESSAGE
DISMISS
VIEW
The phones keep going off.
I just messaged the victim's contacts
that didn't respond before you arrived.
People will turn on their phones
for a police inspection.
Let's call in those three and ask them.
Why did they ignore the
victim's calls and messages?
BEIKA AQUARIUM
I got scared, is all.
I met him when he hit on me last week.
Nakagiri Kanoko (27)
Aquarium Guest
And something seemed a little sketchy.
I had a feeling I shouldn't get involved.
Wow.
She's wearing a miniskirt, reeks of perfume,
and is about 160 centimeters.
What are you looking at?
Oh, uh, nothing.
See? Didn't I tell you?
So you're the one who came to
the aquarium with the victim?
Yes.
I said I liked dolphins, so he
invited me to the aquarium.
So you saw the dolphin show?
Yeah, with him.
But he went to the bathroom during
the show and never came back.
He missed the whole dolphin show.
I went looking for him to give him
an earful, but that was a shock.
He was dead and bleeding.
I had an even bigger shock later...
when I got a call from his phone!
Everyone around me said he'd
been stabbed, so I ignored it.
I thought whoever stabbed him
might be coming for me.
Why did you think that?
He was having a sketchy
conversation on his phone.
Something about,
"I'll definitely get the money."
W-Wait a minute! Do you think I did it?
Y-You can't be serious! I didn't do it!
I have the video to prove it.
Video proof?
I filmed the dolphin show so
I could show him when he got back.
Here it is.
See? This is it.
The front row is soaked!
Hilarious!
You found his body before noon, right?
Yes.
The dolphin show
ended at exactly 12 o'clock.
I filmed the whole dolphin show.
My voice is on the video.
Isn't this an alibi?
I-I suppose so.
BEIKA AQUARIUM
What? Shumoto-kun was the victim?
Ojiro Naho (26)
Aquarium Guest
I heard a man had been stabbed,
but I never thought it'd be him.
What was your relationship with the victim?
He was my ex-boyfriend.
It's been over a year since we broke up.
Why did you ignore his call?
He kept trying to get back together.
And I was on a date today.
So I turned off my phone.
Were you with your boyfriend
the whole time?
Yes.
This is him.
BEIKA AQUARIUM
You can ask him.
But a lover's testimony is...
Come to think of it,
I was filming when it happened.
R-Really?
It's been ten minutes,
but nothing's happening.
It's coming.
Ran, go back to the entrance
and call an employee.
We're in the shot.
Seriously?
What?
Hurry!
Shinichi.
What was that?
That's my boyfriend's voice.
Something seems to have happened.
Should we check it out?
No—
You certainly seem to have taken this video.
Why was Shumoto-kun here?
He was on a date with his girlfriend.
I see. Then maybe he just called
to introduce her to me.
BEIKA AQUARIUM
What?
Are you dating Ojiro Naho-san?
Y-Yeah. How did you know?
Jinbe Kodai (28)
Aquarium Guest
She just told us.
And that the man killed here
today was her ex-boyfriend.
What?
Someone killed Naho's ex-boyfriend?
Really?
Yes.
Jinbe-san.
You knew her ex, didn't you?
O-Of course not!
It's news to me!
But your contact information
was on his phone.
You also ignored the message I sent you.
What? Oh, you mean the one that
said, "Contact me immediately"?
I've received prank messages from that
address before, so I deleted it right away.
I've gotten them a lot lately.
"Click to see my secret."
Shady ones like that.
You're saying they came from
Naho's ex-boyfriend?
Yes, it seems that way.
By the way, like Ojiro-san, you seem to have
been filming when the crime took place.
Oh, right. You mean this video?
Ran, go back to the entrance
and call an employee.
What?
Hurry!
Shinichi.
What was that?
Something seems to have happened.
Should we check it out?
No, let's not get involved—
There are ten minutes
of video preceding this.
We were going to upload
our videos to our blogs later.
You're welcome to watch
the whole thing.
In that case, we will.
BEIKA AQUARIUM
Inspector Megure.
We compared Nakagiri-san's dolphin
show video to those of other guests.
It was definitely taken
when the murder occurred.
I see.
The other suspects' videos weren't
filmed by fixed cameras either.
They were filmed by hand.
But why did the culprit
choose that tunnel?
Hallways with standard tanks are
too dark to see more than silhouettes.
Why did they choose
that brightly lit tunnel specifically?
Shinichi?
Oh, right. Ran, let me borrow your phone.
I forgot mine.
Okay, but don't break it.
My dad finally bought me this one.
Sure.
Sorry, but could you turn around?
What? Turn around?
W-Wait, what?
What are you doing?
I thought the tunnel might
have some significance.
That's because there are
fish everywhere you look.
It feels like you're at
the bottom of the ocean.
The front row is soaked!
Something seems to have happened.
Should we check it out?
No—
That's why it's a romantic place for a date.
Wait, Shinichi?
That's it!
So that's why the culprit chose it!
This place that appears
surrounded by the ocean!
BEIKA AQUARIUM
Inspector Megure.
The guests are demanding to know
when they can leave.
We're having them wait
in the dolphin show area.
But we haven't identified the culprit yet.
Perhaps the culprit fled the aquarium
immediately after stabbing the victim.
It did take a few minutes to seal the exits.
But the cameras there didn't capture any
suspicious persons leaving in a hurry, right?
Then let's have the guests leave.
What?
Except those three suspects, of course.
BEIKA AQUARIUM
Wh-What's going on?
Everyone else has left.
Why do we have to stay?
I showed you the video
that proves my alibi, didn't I?
You saw mine, too.
Mine, too.
Yes, but one of you filmed an odd video.
It practically told us you had done it.
D-Don't tell me it's my dolphin show video.
Now, now. Hear him out.
It's true, isn't it?
These two are a couple. They can make
sure they're telling the same story.
B-But...
Let's see...
You're Nakagiri Kanoko-san, correct?
Yes, that's right.
Your video was awful.
It was shaky, and the sound
quality was terrible.
The front row is soaked!
Hilarious!
No one could watch that.
I-I couldn't help that.
After all, I—
That's right. It's only natural.
After all, you're an amateur.
What?
Most amateur videos are like that.
Compared to yours,
Jinbe-san's video was fantastic.
You got a clear shot of a
leisurely swimming shark.
And that makes me the killer?
No.
You're just used to taking videos.
You were going
to upload it to your blog, too.
If you've uploaded numerous videos,
you must've learned to shoot good ones.
What? Then...
Yes. The problem is your girlfriend's.
What?
Ojiro Naho-san's video.
Yes. The problem is your girlfriend's.
What?
Ojiro Naho-san's video.
Wh-What's wrong with my video?
This is Ojiro-san's video.
This is Jinbe-san's video.
Notice anything different between them?
J-Just that mine's horizontal
and hers is vertical.
Yes.
Normally, if you wanted to shoot
a long fish like a shark,
you'd shoot horizontally like Jinbe-san.
You'd want its whole body in the frame.
But Ojiro-san's video is vertical,
and sure enough...
the shark quickly cuts through
the frame and disappears.
I-I wasn't trying to film the shark.
That's not all that's strange.
Normally, people avoid walking into the shot
when they see someone filming.
Like you see in Jinbe-san's video.
But no one does that in Ojiro-san's.
They walk right through the shot.
It's as though they had
no idea she was filming.
I-I...
It's no wonder they didn't notice.
Because Ojiro-san placed her phone...
inside the fold of Jinbe-san's hat
to film her video.
You'd have to look very closely to notice
a white phone in a white hat.
This allowed her to film a video that
looks like she took it from behind him.
That's why she chose this tunnel.
With fish on all sides,
fish will appear in the shot
no matter which way you shoot.
But wouldn't he notice
if she put that in his hat?
She probably said something
was on his hat, took it off,
inserted the phone, and put it back on.
It takes only a second to remove the phone.
And her video went blurry
at one point, remember?
That was likely
when she removed it.
But people subconsciously move their heads.
The video shouldn't be so steady.
Don't worry about that.
After all, her boyfriend is wearing
a brace for his injured neck.
He can't suddenly move his head.
H-How did you know?
When I spoke from your side
during your interview,
you turned your entire body
instead of just your neck.
While looking at your video, you also held
your phone directly in front of your face.
That's how I knew you couldn't look down
or turn your head due to a neck injury.
Then while he was filming,
Ojiro-san killed him?
Yes.
She found the victim waiting for her in this
tunnel and used a stun gun to knock him out.
Then she stabbed him in the heart and
returned to Jinbe-san to retrieve her phone.
I'm surprised no one saw her.
It didn't matter if anyone saw her.
If she takes off her coat,
raises her skirt, and puts on a hat,
she looks like a different person.
It's dark outside this bright tunnel.
It would have been easy enough to change.
Unfortunately, there was
one thing you couldn't change.
Yes, these gloves.
Since they're reversible, you've
flipped them inside out to hide it...
I knew it.
The victim's blood is on your right finger.
H-How did you know?
The photo you took with your boyfriend.
Based on your clothes and the
background, you took it today.
BEIKA AQUARIUM
But your gloves were a different color.
No one walks around with two pairs.
And you took that photo with your right hand.
You also showed the inspector
your phone with your right hand.
You're clearly right-handed.
But you removed your left glove and
used your phone with your left.
Those facts,
and the fact that some blood seeped through
the bag the culprit used to stab the victim,
lead to this conclusion.
We'll have forensics examine the—
Hurry up and examine it, then!
I'd like to get that man's
blood off me as soon as possible.
Th-Then, Naho, does that mean you...
Yes, that's right.
Have you heard of revenge porn?
It's when an ex-lover plasters
embarrassing photos of someone online.
He said he sent a few to you.
So those shady messages...
That's right.
They contained photos of me
I don't want anyone seeing.
You deleted them without opening them,
but he threatened to call you next.
How'd he even get my contact information?
When I went to his place to break up
because I'd found someone new,
he looked through my phone
while I was in the bathroom.
"If you don't want your boyfriend, job, and
family seeing these photos, give me money."
"I'm up to my neck in debt."
So I spilled his blood instead.
But I screwed up.
If I hadn't spilled blood on my gloves and
reversed them, you may not have known.
No.
It was obvious even if you hadn't.
What?
In Jinbe-san's video, you were
wearing both of your gloves.
You took one off
when you used your left hand,
which means those gloves must
prevent you from using a smartphone.
But you've been pretending that you filmed
a smartphone video with those gloves on.
It was proof you'd done something
that required you to wear them.
It was a simple deduction.
BEIKA AQUARIUM
You should call it off.
After what happened, you shouldn't
use your Romantic Reunion Plan there.
You're right.
Aw, man, it's raining.
Let's run home.
Wait, your hood!
What?
My phone!
No way.
Why was it inside my hood?
Sorry.
I was thinking of where
the culprit put her phone.
I just remembered I put it in your hood.
How could you do this? I just got it!
Don't cry.
I'll buy you a new one.
This sucks! Nothing good
ever happens when I'm with you!
Things kept happening when
we went to America, too...
Fine, then.
Tropical Land.
I'll take you there.
Tropical Land?
That's a cheerful sounding place.
They're building one in Tokyo.
I'm sure nothing will happen
at an amusement park.
I'll go only if you'll pay for everything.
What?
Fine, then how about paying
if I win my karate tournament?
Hey, wait.
Last year, you placed second.
And the third-year who won
quit the team, right?
It's a promise!
What?
I don't have much of an allowance...
And if you're buying me a phone, get a sea
cucumber strap from the aquarium, too.
Okay, okay.
But if you're planning to win, you'd
better get that right hand healed soon.
What?
Come to think of it, earlier...
But it looks like you have
another reason you can't cook.
Hey, Shinichi.
How'd you know about my right hand?
When you got Sonoko's message,
you just checked your messages from her
and your mom but didn't reply.
On top of that,
you were using your left hand.
You probably hurt your right hand and
weren't dexterous enough to write a message.
Since you didn't remove your glove,
you probably bandaged your hand.
But you seem determined
to win your tournament,
so it's just a sprained finger, right?
Yeah. It happened during karate practice.
But if it doesn't get better
and you don't win,
I won't have to pay for your visit.
It'll definitely get better,
and I'll definitely win.
And I'll make you spend a fortune on me.
And so...
I'm here to check out
Tropical Land in advance.
Mystery Coaster and...
Dragon Coaster, huh?
Which should I choose?
Ran is scared of ghosts, though.
I guess we'll go with the Dragon Coaster.
Sheesh!
The Mystery Coaster was so scary!
It's not like those ghosts were real.
No, we'll go with
the Mystery Coaster after all.
Whew, it's totally dark out.
Well, I found some decent attractions and
rides, and places to get lunch and dessert.
This should be plenty.
A fountain?
There's one here, too?
Maybe it seems out of character,
but this is who I am.
Honestly, he's so cold.
Just like ice cream.
But ice cream...
is sweet, you know.
Is this guy for real?
Talk about embarrassing!
Don't be so cringy.
But ending the day
at this fountain could be good.
Yeah. I'm definitely coming here with Ran.
This ice cream is good, isn't it?
Yeah.
But I never did get
to visit this fountain.
30 years, huh?
Don't miss the next episode.
Isn't that amazing?
The anime's 30th-anniversary
year is now starting!